(大蛇丸)本当に
礼儀を知らない子ね。
You really don't have
any manners do you, child?
目上の人間に
話しかけるときは➡
When you address someone
who's higher-ranking than you...
ちゃんと
顔を見せて話すのが礼儀よ。
it's common courtesy
to show your face.
(ナルト)ぐあぁぁぁっ!!
ぐわっ ぐぅぅっ…。
ぐっ ぐぁっ…。
ぐっ… ぐあぁぁぁっ!!
《サクラ : あんなに
傷だらけになって…》
He's covered with wounds...
ぐあぁぁぁぁっ!!
(ヤマト)終わったか。
Looks like it's over...
Naruto!
ナルト～ッ!!
The Secret of the Battle!
いいわ… 聞きましょう。
All right... I'll listen to you.
(サイ)実は ダンゾウ様は
あの木ノ葉崩し以来➡
To tell the truth,
ever since the Destruction
of the Leaf incident,
大蛇丸様との接触の機会を➡
Danzo has been yearning...
ずっと 切望されておいででした。
for an opportunity to come in contact
with you, Lord Orochimaru.
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
《サクラ : 傷の治りが遅い…。
His wounds are slow to heal...
今までのナルトなら 九尾のチャクラで
回復が もっと早かったのに》
Up to now,
Naruto has always been a fast healer
using the Nine-Tailed Chakra...
((自来也 : ナルトは
九尾状態において➡
Naruto, being in
the Nine-Tail's state ...
チャクラが象る妖狐の衣に
守られているようにみえるが➡
At first glance, it appears that
he is being protected
by the Nine-tail's Cloak created
by the Chakra...
実際には 逆に妖狐の衣によって
体に ダメージを受け続けていた。
But in actuality,
his body is continuing to suffer damage
from the Nine-tail's Cloak
４本目の尾が出たとき
妖狐の衣をまとった やつの体は➡
After the fourth tail formed,
his body, wrapped in
the Nine-Tail's Cloak, grew bloodied...
(血まみれ…
重傷を負いながら暴れていた))
and he thrashed about
despite suffering serious injuries.
《自来也様の言っていた
４本目が…➡
The fourth tail that Jiraiya
was talking about...
まさか これほどとは…》
I wouldn't have imagined that
it would be as powerful as this...
うっ…！
ヤマト隊長…。
Captain Yamato...
ナルトを止めた さっきの術…。
That Jutsu that stopped Naruto
earlier on...
(サクラ)あの術 私にも
教えてくれませんか。
Would you teach me that Jutsu...?
That's not possible...
それはムリだよ。
木ノ葉の中で
あの術を使えるのは➡
The only person in the Leaf Village
who can use that Jutsu is me,
初代様の細胞と適合できた
ボクだけさ。
since I inherited the First Hokage's cells.
あの術は 九尾のチャクラを
ムリヤリ 力で押さえ込むもので➡
What that Jutsu does is
forcibly suppress the Nine-Tail's Chakra...
そのための 特別な力を
もたない者には➡
It's impossible for someone
without that special power to use it.
決して 使いこなせる
ものではないんだ。
実験体である コピーのボクの力は➡
My power, which is just
an experimental copy,
オリジナルの初代様とまでは
いかないけどね。
is certainly not on the same level as
the First Hokage's original.
What Naruto has hanging around
his neck is something
ナルトが首にかけているものは➡
初代 火影様の
持っていた物でね…。
that belonged to the First Hokage...
(ヤマト)初代 火影様の
チャクラにだけ呼応する➡
It's a Chakra crystal that
only resonates
チャクラの結晶石なんだよ。
to the First Hokage's Chakra.
(ヤマト)その首飾りで
人柱力のチャクラを制御できる。
With that necklace,
one can control a Jinchuriki's Chakra.
初代 火影様が
火影たりえたのも➡
It is said that this power is
the very reason
この力があったからだと
いわれている。
that the First Hokage
became the Hokage.
And it's also the reason that
ボクが この隊の隊長に
選ばれた理由も それさ。
I was chosen to be
the Captain of this team...
It's always like this...
いつもそう…。
All I can ever do for Naruto...
私がナルトにしてあげられるのは➡
ほんの小さなことだけ…。
are the smallest things.
It's not important whether
the things you do are large or small.
できることの 大きい 小さいは
問題じゃないよ。
What's important...
(ヤマト)大切なのは…。
ナルトを思う気持の大きさでしょ。
is the magnitude of the feelings
you have for Naruto.
サクラ… 君を見ていたらわかる。
Sakura... I can tell that when
I look at you.
You truly...
君は 本当は…。
サクラ… ちゃん…。
S-Sakura...
Owww!
いててっ…。
ナルト…！
Naruto...!
あれ… オレ どうしたんだっけ？
What happened to me...?
大蛇丸の野郎を追っかけて…。
I was chasing that jerk Orochimaru...
and then...
それから…。
それから… それから
何したんだっけ？
And then, what did I do after that?
なぁ サクラちゃん…。
Hey, Sakura...
Huh?
あれ？ サクラちゃん なんで
泣いてんだってばよ？
Why are you crying, Sakura?
うぅん 目にゴミが…。
I just got something in my eyes...
あぁっ！ さては毒舌のサイに➡
That acid-tongued Sai said something
abusive to you again, right?
また何か傷つくこと
言われたんだな！
ブス！ とか 怪力！ とか。
Like, "You're ugly!"
Or, "You're Herculean!"
あの野郎…。
That jerk!
サイは 怪力なんて
言ってないでしょうが！
Sai hasn't called me Herculean...!
あれ？ そっ そうだっけ？
R-Really?
勝手に増やすな… この野郎！
Don't make up stuff...
You jerk!
そういえば ヤマト隊長 サイは？
By the way...
Captain Yamato...
Where's Sai?
ダンゾウ様の話は以上です。
That's everything that Danzo
asked me to convey.
興味深い話ね。
That's extremely interesting...
で その話
何を根拠に信じればいいの？
And...about that story...
Why should I believe it?
(カブト)どういうことです？
What's going on here?
まぁ 落ち着きなさい カブト。
Just calm down...Kabuto.
(大蛇丸)その子は 今日から
私たちの部下になるのよ。
That child is going to be one of
our subordinates starting today.
信用できるんですか？
Can you trust...this guy...?
この男…。
そこの封筒の中を見てください。
Look inside that envelope.
ダンゾウ様から あなたへです。
It's for you, from Danzo.
これは…。
This is...
中身は？
What does it say?
カブト… その子を放してやりなさい。
Kabuto, let go of that child
その子も一緒に連れていくわ。
We're taking that child along with us.
サイとやら… じゃあ 行こうかしら。
Sai...was it?
Shall we go then...?
やはりな…。
Just as I thought...
ヤマト隊長？
ん？
Captain Yamato?
サイは…。
Sai is...
少し待ってくれ！
Wait a moment...
ん？
《橋が…》
The bridge...
アイツには一応
温泉地で仕込んでおいたけどな。
I did plant one on him back at
the hot springs, just in case...
まぁ いいか…
このままで追ってやる！
Oh well. I'll continue
the pursuit as is.
こう見えても
追跡は得意なほうでね。
I might not look it,
but pursuit is actually one of
my strong points.
ヤマト隊長…。
あぁ そうだったね。
Captain Yamato...
Oh yeah...
サイなら 今
大蛇丸と一緒に移動中だよ。
Right now, Sai is...
traveling together with Orochimaru.
あっ…。
えっ？
一緒に!?
Together with...?
どういうことです？
What does that mean?
２人とも ボクについてきな！
Both of you follow me.
まだ土が やわらかいってばよ。
The earth is still soft.
橋は壊れてるし
ここは こんなになっちまって…。
The bridge is busted...
and this place is in
such an awful state...
いったい
何があったんだってばよ！
What the heck...happened?
覚えてないのか？
Don't you remember?
えっ？
う～ん…。
《やはり 自来也様が
おっしゃっていたとおりか…》
So it's just as
Master Jiraiya said, huh...?
((自来也 : 怒りが引き金となり➡
His anger becomes the trigger...
妖狐の尾が生え 増えていった。
And as the number of Fox Spirit tails
he grew increased,
その妖狐の尾が
３本目のときまでは➡
he maintained consciousness
up until the third tail.
アイツも意識を保っていたが➡
４本目で ついに見境がなくなり➡
But by the fourth tail,
he had lost all rationality...
(破壊衝動に支配されていった))
and was controlled
by destructive impulses.
そういえばオレって
なんで気絶してたんだ？
Come to think of it...
why was I unconscious?
(サクラ)大蛇丸に やられて➡
You were unconscious because
you got creamed by Orochimaru.
気絶していたのよ…。
えっ？
マジかよ!? チクショウ!!
Are you serious?!
Damn!
Sai's things are scattered
all over the place...
サイの荷物が 散らばってる…。
でも… なぜ この絵本が…？
But why is this here...?
((へぇ～ 絵本かぁ。
A picture book...
This looks interesting...
それ 行く途中に
見せてもらってもいい？
Hey, can I take a look at it
along the way?
それは ダメだよ。
No, you can't...
It's not finished yet...
これ… まだ 完成してないから…。
それに… 人には
渡さないことにしてるんだ。
and I never hand it over
to anyone as a matter of policy.
(サイ)これは… 兄さんのだからね))
Because this belonged
to my elder brother.
この絵本は サイにとっては
大切なもののはず…。
Sai valued this picture book...
それを こんなところへ…。
But despite that,
here it is in a place like this.
(ヤマト)そんな 大切なものを
置いていくくらいだ。
If he had to leave something
so valuable behind,
(ヤマト)さしもの アイツも➡
it demonstrates that he was in
a tense state in front of Orochimaru.
大蛇丸を前に
緊張していたのかな。
まるで 見ていたみたいに
知っているんですね。
You seem to know that as if
you witnessed it yourself.
Until earlier on...
(ヤマト)さっきまで
ボクの木分身を ここにおいて➡
I placed my Wood Clone here, and
was in communication with it,
ここに 仕込んである無線で➡
using the wireless radio
implanted here.
連絡を 取り合っていたからな。
サイに… 何が あったんですか!?
What happened to Sai?
サイは… ここで 大蛇丸と
会話の やりとりをしたあと➡
After Sai's...conversation
with Orochimaru,
大蛇丸と カブトのあとに
ついていった…。
he went away with Orochimaru
and Kabuto.
えっ!? どういうことだってばよ!?
What does that mean?!
会話の内容は？
What did they talk about?
They were talking a distance away...
(ヤマト)会話は遠くて
聞き取れなかったみたいだ。
so I couldn't make out
the conversation.
う～ん…
なんの話を したんだろう？
I wonder what
they were talking about?
脅されて 連れていかれたのかも。
He might have been kidnapped
and taken away.
No, it seems that he approached
Orochimaru of his own volition...
いや… そんな感じじゃ なかった。
自ら 大蛇丸に近づき
何かを 渡していた。
and handed him something.
まるで 大蛇丸に
取り入ろうとするかのようにね。
It was just like he was trying
to cozy up to Orochimaru...
ちょ…
ちょっと 待ってくれってばよ！
W-Wait a minute!
いくら アイツが すげえ イヤなヤツでも
オレたちを 裏切るなんてことは…。
Even a disgusting guy like him
wouldn't betray us, would he?
いや… あるかも…。
No, there is a possibility...
((綱手 : 昔…
三代目 火影のイスを巡って➡
A long time ago,
he competed with
the late Sarutobi Sensei...
亡き 猿飛先生と争った人物だ。
over the position of
the Third Hokage.
(綱手)三代目とは違い
ガチガチな 合理的思考に基づく強硬➡
Unlike the Third Hokage,
he's the leader of
a hard-line military faction...
based on rigid logic...
and is Sai's superior.
武闘派路線の主導者で…➡
サイの 上司だ。
初代 火影の孫で➡
He hates me because...
I'm the granddaughter
of the First Hokage...
(穏健派だった 三代目の
教え子の私が 嫌いなのさ…))
as well as a student of
the Third Hokage who was moderate...
Captain Yamato, do you know
a person named Danzo...?
ヤマト隊長は ダンゾウって人のこと…。
(ヤマト)知っているよ。
Yes, I know him.
誰なんだってばよ？ それ…。
Who is...that guy?
かつて 三代目と対立した
タカ派の男…。
A man from the Hawk Faction who
in the past opposed the Third Hokage.
サイの上司で…➡
He's Sai's boss...
三代目の意志を よく思ってない
じじいよ…。
And an old gramps who doesn't
think well of the Third Hokage's will.
ダンゾウは サイを使って➡
Danzo may be using Sai to make
some kind of move.
何かを しようと
しているのかもしれない…。
もしかすると…
サイは そのダンゾウから➡
It's possible that...
Sai may have been given
a mission...
ボクらの隊の任務とは 別の…➡
by Danzo that is separate from ours...
何らかの 極秘任務を…➡
There is a possibility that
he was charged...
命ぜられていた可能性も
あるな…。
なっ…!? それじゃあ アイツは
オレたちとの任務を 利用して➡
大蛇丸のヤツと 接触するために
動いてたってことか!?
そういうことね。
ここから さらに
強引な推測だが…➡
考えられないことも ないことと…
心して 聞いてくれ。
ダンゾウは…➡
今の 木ノ葉を
潰す気かもしれない！
今日は
「初代 火影の首飾り」についてだ。
初代 火影の持ち物だった
この 首飾りには➡
特殊な鉱石が 使われていて➡
売れば 山 ３つは
買えるといわれる代物だ。
初代 火影の孫
綱手様にとっては➡
おじいさまの形見というわけだ。
かつて 綱手様は この首飾りを
弟の 縄樹君。
そして 恋人のダンさんに
プレゼントしたことがあった。
しかし 最愛の２人は
共に 戦乱のなか➡
志半ばで 命を落としてしまった。
以来 この首飾りは
綱手様以外の持ち主を認めず➡
着けた人間は 必ず死ぬ と
言われるようになった。
それから 長い年月が経ち➡
首飾りは ２人と
同じ夢をもつ少年に 託された。
それが ナルトだ。
吉と出るか 凶と出るか…。
これこそが 綱手様の
最大のギャンブルなのかもしれないな。